MUHAMMAD AIMAN SYAKIR BIN MOHD ZULKIFLI

+60 18 9071656 | Alor Setar, Kedah

aiman.zulkifli10@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | My Portfolio



SUMMARY

I am a recent graduate actively pursuing an entry/junior-level Front-end Developer position. I am currently working as an TM One Protégé at Telekom Malaysia Berhad, where I am gaining hands-on experience in IT operations and solutions. Previously, I completed a 6-month internship at MIMOS Berhad under the Artificial Intelligence Department, where I developed skills in AI integration, data visualization, and web development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Telekom Malaysia Berhad TM Protégé

(Oct 2024 - Present)

 Assisted in conducting on-site cabling surveys to assess the infrastructure for network installation and maintenance.

MIMOS Berhad

Internship Trainee under Artificial Intelligence Department

(Aug 2023 - Jan 2024)

- Created and designed a variety of charts and plotted the charts into the widget library available inside ThingsBoard. Additionally, I applied the charts into the ThingsBoard dashboard using Echarts and D3.js.
- Performed comprehensive data collection and subsequent feature extraction. Assigned to
 collect electrical signals utilizing Sbench6 acquisition software, the focus was on capturing high
 sampling rates of instantaneous current and voltage magnitudes in preparation for lab
 experiments.
- Testing on HDF5 Converter for NILMTK: Conducted experiments to test the generated data in HDF5 format with NILMTK's Experiment API.
- Involved in collecting seq2point experiment results. Responsibilities included handling one of
 the server ports used for model training experiments, as well as ensuring efficient data
 processing processes to enable AI algorithm development and optimization.
- Developed a simple interactive visualization for Non-Intrusive Load Monitoring (NILM) using Python's Flask framework, HTML, and Plotly to create interactive charts.
- Conducted research and evaluation of transcription software with AI meeting assistant functionalities which need to analysed features, language support, and affordability.
- Conducted preliminary surveys on Text to Speech (TTS), Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR), and AI Meeting Assistant technologies.

SKILLS

Languages : English (Professional Working Proficiency), Malay (Native or Bilingual

Proficiency)

Programming Languages

: HTML/CSS, Java, JavaScript, Basic in C++, Basic in Python

Libraries/Framework

: Basic in React, Angular, Bootstrap, NumPy, Pandas, Plotly, Flask,

Echarts, D3.js

Tools/Platforms/Environment: Jupyter Notebook, Visual Studio Code, Figma, Node.js

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Information & Communication Technology (Hons)

(Feb 2021 - Jan 2024)

Management & Science University (MSU)

- CGPA: 3.26
- Final Year Project (FYP): E-Portfolio Content Management System Version 2.0

Foundation in Information Technology

(Jul 2019 - Jan 2021)

Management & Science University (MSU)

CGPA: 2.51

CERTIFICATION

Malaysian University English Test (MUET)

(Achieved on May 2022)

Band Achieved: 3.5

SEMINAR / WORKSHOP / COURSE ATTENDED

- AWS Hands-on Workshop Amazon Cognito, API Gateway Security and IoT
- AWS 101 Workshop
- Knowledge Sharing Session on Non-Intrusive Load Monitoring
- Advancements in Renewable Energy Integration and Power Electronics for a Sustainable Future
- AWSome Day Online Conference
- Research Colloquium Series

PROJECT

E-Portfolio Content Management System Version 2.0 (GitHub)

Developed an E-Portfolio Content Management System Version 2.0, a web-based platform hosted on the internet. Utilized a content management system (CMS) to enable users to effortlessly create, manage, and modify content for their digital portfolios without requiring technical expertise. Leveraged MySQL, an Oracle-backed open-source relational database management system, to securely store and manage diverse forms of information, ensuring accessibility from anywhere. The system serves as a modern alternative to the manual paper-based portfolio assessment method, streamlining the process and enhancing efficiency in educational or professional settings.

REST Countries API with Colour Theme Switcher (GitHub / Live View)

 A responsive web application built with React that fetch and displays data from the REST Countries API. The app allows users to search for countries, filter by region, view detailed information about each country, and navigate to neighbouring countries. It also features a light/dark mode theme toggle for enhanced user experience across different devices.

Personal Portfolio (GitHub / Live View)

Showcasing my skills, experiences, and projects.

REFERENCE

1. Nor Aziah Amirah

(External Supervisor MIMOS Berhad) +6012-2339565

2. Nadia Adila Binti Mohd Zulkifli

(Full Stack Developer) +6018-4676406